# IAN SNYDER

# Lead Engineer

Portfolio

<u>LinkedIn</u>

GitHub

iansnyder@gmail.com

## Game Dev

Unity: C#

Unreal: C++

Godot: GDScript

Switch, Xbox, Steam, Epic

iOS and Android

Client/Server Networking

Visual Scripting

PlayFab

Perforce & Git

Substance Suite

#### Leadership

 Agile Project and Team Management

 Enterprise Mentorship & Education

# **Certifications & Awards**

Unity Certified Instructor

 Unity Certified Professional Programmer & Artist

Winning Entry Dreamhack Austin

 Team MVP NCSoft

 1st Place MIGS Battle of the Studios 7 hour game jam

#### Education

May 2008

# **B.S. Mathematics**Minor in **Art & Design**

Texas State University

San Marcos, TX

#### **Profile**

I've been a game developer for over 15 years, with extensive gameplay programming and design experience in Unity and Unreal. I've shipped 9 games as an indie developer and at large studios, and I've provided advanced technical consultation for AAA studios.

My specialties are creating rapid prototypes and optimization. I confidently lead cross-disciplinary teams because of my skills in all aspects of game development.

# **Professional Experience**

February 2024 - Present

Full-time Remote

# Lead Unity Gameplay Engineer - PLAYA3ULL GAMES

 Currently leading a team of developers to create an online MP TCG with direct reports, hiring responsibilities, contracts, project management, etc.

Responsible for project architecture, Client/Server network programming, backend development, PlayFab Linux server containerization and deployment

August 2017 - May 2024

Omaha, NE

# Lead Faculty of Game Dev - Metropolitan Community College

Led collaborative VR/AR project for public exhibit at the Kaneko art gallery

Coded multiple Unreal VR projects with HDR, a multinational architecture firm

Developed a Unity C# app for the Microsoft HoloLens

November 2019 - Present

Contract

# **Trainer for North America** - Unity Technologies

 Led dozens of advanced training workshops for AAA and indie game studios, and AEC clients covering C# programming, physics, memory management, Addressables, optimization, debugging, writing readable maintainable code, etc.

Taught rapid prototyping techniques using C# and Unity

Led trainings and provided technical support for enterprise partners

January 2018 - Present

Self-employed

#### Founder & Gameplay Engineer - Studio Nisse

 Developed and published Skycadia, a physics-based flying sim for Nintendo Switch, Xbox Series X|S & One, and Steam using best engineering standards

Engineered online feature functionality for all platforms

Optimized to support a wide range of platforms

Trained and mentored over a dozen interns in all aspects of game development

 Other projects: UE5 Vehicle Game, Tactics Game Template, Dreadmark Racing, Brownie: Spirit of the Woods

2016 - 2017

San Mateo, CA

#### Senior Game Designer - NCSoft

 Overhauled design of combat system: overall vision, programmed rapid prototype in C#, UI, and systems

2014 - 2016

Las Cruces, NM

Montreal, QC

# Lead Faculty of Game Development - Doña Ana Community College

Programmed a VR application used for pain management in healthcare

Started the Crytek VR First lab, the first community college location in the world

Programmed VR experiences with Virgin Galactic

2008 – 2014

## Game Designer and Lead Environment Artist - Gameloft

Gangstar Vegas, Asphalt 7: Heat, Gangstar Rio, Asphalt 6: Adrenaline, Dungeon Hunter 2, GT Racing: Motor Academy